olanmills.com 2012-12-31

# Lifetouch Photography Services - Privacy & Terms

### **US Privacy Statement  ** ([Canadian customers click here](http://www.lifetouch.ca/privacy.aspx)) (Your California Privacy Rights)

This website (the “Lifetouch Site”) is owned and operated by Lifetouch Inc. (“Lifetouch”) along with its wholly-owned subsidiaries Lifetouch National School Studios Inc., Lifetouch Portrait Studios Inc., Lifetouch Church Directories and Portraits Inc. (U.S. and Canada), Lifetouch Canada Inc., Lifetouch Services Inc. and their divisions doing business as JCPenney Portraits, Target Studios, Olan Mills, Prestige Portraits, Sportography, Flash Digital Portraits and Cilento Photography, (“the Lifetouch Companies”). Lifetouch is a trusted provider of photographic products and services to communities, schools, churches, day care centers and families throughout the United States and Canada. At Lifetouch, we are sensitive to the privacy concerns of visitors to our websites. Though we do not obtain any personal information that individually identifies you (e.g., your name, address, phone number, e-mail address, etc.) unless you affirmatively provide it to us, many visitors do choose to provide us with such information. This policy explains our online information practices pertaining to this website and the choices you, as a visitor to this site, can make about the collection and use of your information.

#### What personal information is collected at Lifetouch.com? How is it used?

At the Lifetouch Site, we only collect personally identifiable information about you to the extent you specifically provide it to us. This includes, for example, the information you provide when you contact us through this website to place an order, contact customer service, register for a service, respond to a survey or enter a contest or sweepstakes online. We use this information you share with us

  * to provide the products or services or benefits you request,
  * to develop and improve our products and services,
  * to improve the content of our site and its usefulness to you, and
  * for our own marketing and promotional purposes.

Lifetouch does not sell, trade or share the information you provide us through this website with unaffiliated third parties for their marketing purposes. We reserve the right to share such information among the Lifetouch Companies and you may receive product and service information from any of them. Information you submit to jcpenneyportraits.com and/or targetstudios.com (operated by Lifetouch Portrait Studios Inc.) may also be shared with the host organization, J. C. Penney Company, Inc. or Target Corporation respectively. Finally, we may also share this information with outside vendors and organizations that provide support services to us such as helping us fulfill customer orders, process credit card orders and the like. If so, these parties are authorized to use the information solely in conjunction with the specific service they provide to or on behalf of Lifetouch.

We may also be required to share information you provide us through this website in other, limited circumstances in which we may share or transfer the information you provide us through this website, for example, to respond to judicial process, to comply with state, federal or local laws, to protect the security or integrity of our databases or website, to take precautions against liability, in the event of a corporate reorganization or, to the extent required by law, to provide information to law enforcement agencies.

#### Safeguarding information

Within the Lifetouch Companies, we protect against unauthorized disclosures by limiting access to employees and contractors of the Lifetouch Companies who need the information to do their jobs. We also give them guidelines for adhering to our confidentiality policies.

In the limited circumstances that we provide information to outside companies, we restrict it to only the information we believe is appropriate to enable them to carry out their responsibilities under our contracts.

We require that the information provided be used only for the specifically authorized purpose and that its confidentiality be maintained.

#### Other information about you

In addition to personal information you provide us through this website, the Lifetouch Site uses technology that lets us know what type of browser you are using, the website from which you enter the Lifetouch Site, and the pages you view as you tour our site. This technology does not identify you personally — it simply helps us compile statistics about our visitors and their use of our site. We use these statistics and share them with third parties to improve our website design and content and in connection with marketing programs.

A "cookie" is a small data file stored by your web browser on your computer's hard drive. Cookies are necessary to use the site. A cookie allows our web server to balance customer traffic on our website to enhance performance of the service. After you end your session the cookie from the web server will remain on your computer until you manually delete it. No personal information is stored on this cookie. Accepting cookies through your web browser is your personal choice. However, if you choose not to accept cookies, you may not be able to take full advantage of some of this website's features.

With respect to customers of Prestige Portraits, we also partner with Google to deliver advertisements about our products and services when you visit other websites across the Internet. These vendors place third party cookies which help us provide you with advertisements that are customized to your particular product preferences and improve the effectiveness of our marketing efforts. You may opt out of Google cookies by going to the [Google Opt-Out Page](http://www.google.com/ads/preferences/html/opt-out.html) and following the directions indicated on that site.   

#### If you do not wish to receive promotional information as a result of using the Lifetouch.com website, what should you do?

Our goal is to inform you about our products and services, including special promotions and coupons. We may contact you by mail or e-mail or telephone to inform you of offers. However, if you are contacted and do not wish to receive further information or contacts, use the means by which you were contacted to indicate you do not want further promotional information or contacts from them. If contacted by mail, return the mail to sender. If contacted by e-mail, reply to the e-mail sender. If telephoned, notify the person telephoning you that you do not want additional contacts from them.

We will act promptly to honor your request and remove your name from the sender’s marketing list. However, even if we remove your name from use in marketing programs, you may still receive communications from the sender if necessary, for example, in connection with a pending order or customer service issue, or from other sources who obtained your contact information before we received your request or from a party other than Lifetouch.

#### Your California Privacy Rights

Under California law, a California resident with whom a Lifetouch Company has an established relationship has the right to request certain information with respect to the types of personal information the company has shared with third parties for their direct marketing purposes, if any, and the identities of those third parties, within the immediately preceding calendar year, subject to certain exceptions. All requests for such information must be in writing and sent by mail or email to our Privacy Office at the address indicated below (“For Further Information”).  

#### Children

The Lifetouch Site does not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under the age of 13. If a child has provided personally identifiable information through the Lifetouch Site, we ask that a parent or guardian contact the Lifetouch Site in writing at 11000 Viking Drive, Suite 400, Eden Prairie, MN 55344, Attention: Privacy Office or [privacyoffice@lifetouch.com](mailto:privacyoffice@lifetouch.com) and we will respond accordingly.

#### No control of third party sites

Please be aware that websites that link to the Lifetouch Site may collect personally identifiable information about you. You should consult the other sites' privacy policies as we have no control over information that is submitted to, or collected by, these third parties.   

#### Your consent

By using the the Lifetouch Site, you consent to our use of your information as described in this Online Privacy Policy. As we implement new technology and introduce new services, we will update our Online Privacy Policy, so we encourage you to review it often. We reserve the right to change our Online Privacy Policy at any time without advance notice. Should any new online policy go into effect, we will post it on this site, and the policy will apply to all information collected.

#### For further information

For further information regarding this website privacy statement or related Lifetouch policies and procedures, please contact: Privacy Office, Lifetouch Inc., 11000 Viking Drive, Eden Prairie, MN 55344; e-mail: [privacyoffice@lifetouch.com](mailto:privacyoffice@lifetouch.com)

Revised August 2012
